once you are satisfied with the content
structure and layout of your
presentation you may wish to add some
animation or transition effects this
will just enhance the appearance of the
presentation when it is being presented
to an audience so at the moment I don't
have any animations or transitions on
the presentation and if I go to the
slide short view and select layer from
start you will see that the first slate
appears instantly and then as I click
each slate simply comes under the screen
instantly and every time I click so to
make some changes to that I'd like to
add a transition effect so that each of
the slate as it comes on the screen it
comes in in a certain manner rather than
just appearing all at once so I'm going
to add the transition effect it up so if
I click on the transitions tab and as
you can see along the top of the
transition there are a range of
transition effects that you can select
from so if you click on one it will
demonstrate how that will apply to the
slate so then you can go through until
you find one that you're happy with and
then you can apply that and I'm going to
go with the split transition and now I
can go on to slay two three four and
five and apply different transitions to
each slate however just for consistency
I do have the option to apply that to
all by just clicking on that button
there in the top right corner I click
apply the wall that there's no applied
that same transition to all of the
slides of which is to demo that by going
to slide shore and then select Leah from
start every time I click as you can see
the slates come in slightly different
rather than instantly they're coming in
a certain manner so again but if you're
not happy with the transition that
you've applied you can always go back in
and make a change and select another one
so once you're happy with your
transition there are another couple of
tools that you could use within here you
contain the actual transition so specify
the transition duration in seconds so if
you want the transition to take longer
you can increase the time on there
again there's also on most clicks or the
transition only occurs when I click the
mouse or that flayed will see on the
screen until I click and also you can
add a sound a transition zone so you can
click on there and you could have
applause our or Bom
so you could select a sound effect to
appear with the transition and I just
have a quick demonstration of that with
applause so if we preview that and as
you can see you can have a for so we'll
just go with your son for that so now
that I've happy with the transitions its
attained to think about adding some
animations so again if I click on the
animations tab and as you can see they
are all grayed out at the moment and I'm
just going to click on slide one and the
reason that all of the animation effects
are grayed out is that they will not
become active until you select an
element within the slate to animate and
as soon as I click on the first piece of
text they all become active and then
again as with the transitions I can just
go through and select the animation but
I wish to use and I think I will go for
the GRU turn and I've applied that so as
you can see there's a number one appear
though that means that I've applied that
animation to that text every element
within the slate can be animated so I'm
going to honor me at the first picture
of the balloon and I'm going to do we
check our board with that
again I can click on the next image in
the slate and select dissolve in and the
seals report I'm going to go back and do
the GRU and turn so once I'm happy with
that I can preview that slate to see how
it will look so that is how the slide
will appear when I actually do the
presentation you can then go on to add
animations to each element within there
so you can add animations to the chart
the text within there all of the title
text the table-saw any element within a
presentation can be animated one of the
things that you need to be aware of
though is that by default it will
automatically set it so the animations
appear on click so when you run the
slideshow you will have to click through
so if you've got a lot of animations
that can take some time and detract from
your work or your focus on exactly what
you're doing so you're presenting it you
would rather have it come in
automatically that can be changed if you
look up on the right hand side the
animations pian has appeared so if I
look along here and see the animations
that have been applied and they are all
selecting are all showing a little mouse
keulen which means a clicks or every
time I click the animation will appear I
can change that by selecting from here
after previous so now a little clock
appears and again I can select after
previous and again after previous and
again after previous you can also select
the duration of the animation so if I
want the animation to take longer I can
increase the timing on that so just for
example to get that up to two seconds
and for the second one I'll take that up
to 3 2.5 seconds
the third one I'll take up to three and
I'll leave the last one alone you also
have the effect options so there's
various tools you can play around with
in there the timings again the triggers
is was the as part of a click sequence
on click and the text animations you can
have the text animate come in all at
once so you can have a look at those
tools and if I just preview this now so
far look at slide one now as you can see
the time for each animation to appear is
slightly different so as I say you can
then go through each of the slate I
animation is required and decide on how
long you want the animation to appear
for or how long whether it's on click or
whether it's just automatic